

Claudia Cecilia Rossi

0054 9 291 4187312 – <u>claudiarossi0707@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/claudiaceciliarossi/

Actual Passports: Argentinian and Italian

https://resume-ccr.herokuapp.com/ (user: guest, pass:1234)

Profile

I have over twenty years of experience in software development. Working in both, face to face and virtual environments, I have covered several roles in which I was able to get adapted to the dynamics of the different changes in programming, offering to my employers the capacity and initiative of self-learning and on-the-job training.

I have always strived to be able to develop with the latest technologies and to be able to meet the expectations of different customers. During the last years, my professional development had an impasse due to my maternity leave.

If I am not selected for this job position, I would really appreciate your consideration to have me as candidate for future opportunities.

Major Achievements

- Led the analysis, development, training and implementation of the Personnel Performance Evaluation system for the Public mining company of Chile, CODELCO, which had 17,000 employees at that time.
- As project manager, led a multidisciplinary team responsible for the first banking website in Argentina: www.e-galicia.com. I was responsible to supervise the work of 10 programmers and graphic designers.

Employment History

Freelance programmer.

Aug 2011 - Aug 2014

IACA Laboratories. Bahia Blanca, Arg. Visual Basic developments to import and process data generated by Bioanalytical Laboratory Instruments for subsequent analysis and delivery of reports to end users. Trained in GLP (Good Laboratory Practices).

Advanced application programmer. Remote

Mar 2006 – Mar 2010

<u>BA Technology</u>. <u>Bahía Blanca</u>, <u>Arg.</u> CODELCO, the public mining company of Chile, had RHPro software. We had to customize the performance development module, to fit with CODELCO's requirements. I was responsible for the requirements analysis and for the

development. Later, I facilitated the training, including both Headquarters in Santiago Chile and a mine in El Salvador. Once project was completed, I was responsible for the maintenance of it.

Assistant programmer.

Mar 2005 – Feb 2006

<u>Solvay. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Temporary replacement of IT personnel in the HR Area. Main responsibilities were maintenance of database and macro developments in Visual Basic for Excel. This information was used for the performance development.

WEB software developer. Remote.

Jan 2001 – Mar 2005

RHPRO (Heidt & Asociados). Buenos Aires, Arg. Application scheduler for INTRANET. Technology used: ASP, SQL Server, Oracle, JavaScript, HTML. Customization of an existing HR management system to meet customers' requirements. I worked remote from home, doing the customizations development and I traveled to Buenos Aires many times to do the analysis requirements, for example for Deloitte&Touche.

Project Manager.

May 1998 - Mar 2001

<u>Technisys. Buenos Aires, Arg.</u> Leader of WEB projects. Tasks consisted of interviews with clients, requirements analysis, planning, work team organization and also applications programming. ASP technology, JavaScript, MySQL, MS SQL Server, HTML, XML. In the 2000s with the emergence of web technology, I was able to lead the development of the first banking/financial websites in Argentina: Previnter, Fondos1784, and the most rewarding for me, www.e-galicia.com. I also participated in the development of the websites for Citibank and VisaHome.

Lieutenant - Data Computing Service.

Mar 1996 – Apr 1998

<u>Argentina Army. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Development of ammunition inventory stock control applications for the "Base de Apoyo Logistico (BAL)" military unit in Pigue, using Clarion.

Advanced application programmer. Remote Jun 1993 – Mar 1996

<u>Systems Solutions. Buenos Aires, Arg.</u> Senior programmer in the 4th generation Progress language, for installation, maintenance and customizations of the Magnus Datasul system. Programming in sequential Progress and afterward in version 7 and higher ones, consequently changing the paradigm to event-driven programming.

Develop and facilitate Progress 7 training, aimed to programmers who filled positions in Joinville (Brazil) and Canale and Danone (Argentina).

I worked remote and traveled for implementations and tests at Mastellone, Quest International, Campo Frio and Elf Lubricants, among others.

<u>Universidad Nacional del Sur. Bahía Blanca, Arg.</u> Assistant Professor A (graduate) in the following courses: "Introduction to Computing", "Data Processing", "Algorithm Structures" and "Programming Languages"

Skills and Competences

- Build strong interpersonal relationship with Customers. Understand and meet their needs.
- High ability to self-learning in new technologies.
- High experience in remote work.
- Deliver training to multifunctional teams.

Education and training

- Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. Universidad Nacional del Sur, Bahia Blanca. 1984 1990
- 1st Certificate English level. 1973 1983 Asociación Bahiense de Cultura Inglesa.
- Diploma in C # .NET. Sep 2018 Dec 2018. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Angular programming. Jun 2019 Jul 2019. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Node Js programming. Oct 2019 Nov 2019. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- Professional Webmaster. March 2021. Currently attending. UTN FRBA e-Learning Center
- IELTS Intensive preparative course. March 2021 –April 2021. www.ielts.org.ar

Personal information

For family needs, I resided, in 2008, three months in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, United States. In 2010, I lived three months in Rayon, Thailand. In 2018, spent one month in Houston, United States. All these cases gave me the opportunity to enhance my English skills and exposed me to personal relationship with people from different cultures.

References

- Mrs. Lila Drittanti, PhD. (+33 (0)7 82 25 1958) linkedin.com/in/liladrittanti/ Paris, France.
 www.markets-listing.com. ldrittanti@gmail.com
- Mrs. Virgina Cuomo, BSc (+54 9 11 51111782). General Director of Quality and PMO.
 Sofrecom Argentina. Buenos Aires, Argentina.
 vvcuomo@gmail.com.
- Monica Wirth, CEH IT Service Management Head at BankUnited, SVP. Fort Lauderdale, FL USA monica.wirth@gmail.com.